<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>adrian</title>
 <link href="http://adrianmcli.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://adrianmcli.com/"/>
 <updated>2015-01-21T16:38:03-08:00</updated>
 <id>http://adrianmcli.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Adrian Li</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>What I learned from Seth Godin's Startup School</title>
   <link href="http://adrianmcli.com/2015/01/21/seth-godin-startup-school/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-21T16:38:02-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://adrianmcli.com/2015/01/21/seth-godin-startup-school</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently finished listening to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.earwolf.com/show/startup-school/&quot;&gt;Seth Godin&amp;#39;s Startup School&lt;/a&gt; podcasts and took notes on the content. Below is the condensed form of what I personally extracted from all 15 episodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Episode 1: Freelancer or Entrepreneur?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;3 things you need to be good at&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you know what to do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you understand, from 10,000 feet, what the smartest people in the industry would tell you is the right thing to do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are you able to do it? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are you capable enough to do the right thing (the thing you need to do)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organizing, marketing, hiring, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you care enough about the project to get hit?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How invested are you into the project?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Lessons from Monopoly&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Every successful business has a monopoly&lt;/strong&gt; - Figure out what it is that you can do, that will cause people to go out of their way to come to you for it. The current entrepreneurial environment is that of a connection economy. Be at the centre of connections, because it is more important than simply selling stuff. If your friends are using a networked product (like Facebook for example), you won&amp;#39;t go to another product even if it may be better. Clearly, it&amp;#39;s not enough to be better, that is the old industrial economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;An Entrepreneur&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An entrepreneur builds something bigger than himself. When you&amp;#39;re a bootstrapper, you have to start by yourself, but eventually you must ask: How do I make it so the people I hire are better at their tasks than I am?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People give you money because they think what you are doing is worth more than it costs. So you as the entrepreneur has the obligation to deliver on that value, or else you won&amp;#39;t have any customers. Therefore, marketing is just telling a story about the value that you can provide that can resonate with people enough that they will give you money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You must figure out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do you tell the story?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who do you tell the story to?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do you create this value?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Episode 2: Adjusting the Course&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hard part is not defining the path, but it&amp;#39;s sticking to the path. It is a very scary and lonely path, especially because a lot of the people around you won&amp;#39;t be able to talk to you about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real entrepreneurship: if the geniuses took two weeks off, will the business keep running?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can be the smartest person in the world, but if the voice in your head pushes you to avoid opportunities, you won&amp;#39;t get ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Questions to ask about your business&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who is it for?&lt;/strong&gt; - Nothing is for everyone, you need to define your market.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do they believe?&lt;/strong&gt; - What are the different world views of the people you are targetting? There will be sub-groups of the groups that you have defined in the first question above. What is the story they are telling themselves?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do they view the world?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How would they view your particular product or service?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How would they respond to the way you market?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have they ever spent cash money to buy something like this before?&lt;/strong&gt; - It is a lot more difficult to sell to people who are not already spending money on a similar product or service. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does this group or sub-group know about you?&lt;/strong&gt; - There&amp;#39;s a huge gulf between people who ahve heard of you and those who are not aware of you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Those people who are aware of you, do they trust you?&lt;/strong&gt; - There&amp;#39;s a big gap between those who are simply aware of you and those who trust you enough to buy from you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;B2B is the same as B2C except that B2B is asking the question: Will this make my boss happy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the connection economy, we have to think about the value your business creates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;3 Kinds of Revenue&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cash&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attention and trust&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Referral&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Episode 3: Creating Scarcity&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would I buy your product or hire your service to solve my problem?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Difference between manipulation and marketing is that with manipulation, you will regret buying it later. But with marketing, you&amp;#39;ll still be glad you bought it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app market is a sucker&amp;#39;s game:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;biggest haystack, and you&amp;#39;re the tiniest needle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;most apps don&amp;#39;t lend themselves to network effects and scale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it is difficult to sell your app before people try&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good network effect
&amp;quot;It works better if my friends used it too&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What problem is my customer waking up with?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your job is not to find more customers for your product, your job is to find more product for your customers. What other tools are available to these customers so that I can use their connections to develop more value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;#39;s the hard part of your business? If there is no hard part, then it&amp;#39;s not going to be a successful business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the time being spent on your logo is just you avoiding doing the hard things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As this thing catches on, does it become more valuable or less valuable?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tribe targetting. You must DEFINE the tribe. Not just simple demographics, but maybe they&amp;#39;re all reading the same magazine, or are fans of the same type of thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Episode 4: Appealing to Consumers&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you selling a product that will appeal to:
- early adopters?
- the masses?
- people who won&amp;#39;t buy unless they need it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to cross the chasm from the early adopters to the masses&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the beginning, look for tribal watering holes where early adopters hang out at. Make them the &amp;quot;insiders&amp;quot;. Make it the perfect product for that small group. Eventually, you might cross the chasm through this community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not attempt to skip the tribe leaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can&amp;#39;t decide on an idea? Think about deciding on lunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Episode 5: Permission and Trust&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you start, figure out how you can get from the tribe to the masses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you don&amp;#39;t insist on sticking to a path that is a wrong path. You need to keep experimenting and keep changing things that are not working. Do not fall in love with a vision in your head. The more degrees of freedom you have, the more likely you will have a business that works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blogging/Content marketing: Commit to writing something for your tribe everyday. Not about yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will never be perfect and proven, so stop thinking of all that before you start doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you build something that will be missed if it was gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Struggling w/ Costs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What assumptions have you made about what you need (that you can actually skip)?
Can I do it faster?
Start with the people who value what you can do instead of trying to pretend to be someone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You do NOT need to launch pretty. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Build trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are people paying for, and can I dramatically provide something with a higher value for the same price?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Episode 6: Raising Money&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to get rid of the work you are using to distract yourself, as opposed to the stuff that is actually difficult and needs to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;#39;s scarce, what&amp;#39;s hard.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Spoil and Deprive</title>
   <link href="http://adrianmcli.com/2015/01/21/spoil-and-deprive/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-21T16:37:59-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://adrianmcli.com/2015/01/21/spoil-and-deprive</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Only those who have their backs against the wall can truly find out what they really want and what they will sacrifice to get there. This is the compliment to my spoil and deprive idea. We have to feel desperate to succeed, or else we never will. How do you make yourself desperate?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s not smart to simply dump all your money into the trash and live in a cardboard box. It will hamper your effectiveness. There is an alternate way to create desperation within yourself, and that is the spoil and deprive cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;re all familiar with the hedonic treadmill. Well, we want to get to the rear edge of the treadmill and feel like we&amp;#39;re about to fall off. But we don&amp;#39;t actually want to fall off (e.g. bankruptcy or damaging your health and safety). We can actually USE the hedonic treadmill to our advantage in this case. By spoiling ourselves and forcing ourselves to experience luxuries, we inexorably will FEEL like we are at the back of the treadmill when our life goes back to &amp;quot;normal&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;tl;dr - Spoil and deprive simulates the desperation required for incredible drive and willpower.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Lessons from Peter Voogd</title>
   <link href="http://adrianmcli.com/2015/01/21/peter-voogd/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-21T15:52:41-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://adrianmcli.com/2015/01/21/peter-voogd</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve been listening to some podcasts, and today I&amp;#39;m going to summarize a couple of them that I found to be particularly valuable. Peter Voogd has went on Hal Elrod&amp;#39;s podcasts twice, and I listened to both of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The links to the podcasts are here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://halelrod.com/36/&quot;&gt;first&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://halelrod.com/55-6-figures/&quot;&gt;second&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;1st Podcast: How to be a game changer&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HOW FAST CAN I IMPLEMENT THIS - this is very important&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start by asking about your ideal outcome:
- What is your vision for business, lifestyle, income in 6-12 months?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;1. Simplicity&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simplify what really matters to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;One-page productivity plan - mastery over information overload&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;contents&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one paragraph vision statement

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;who I am, where I wanna be, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;top values

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;flexibility, financial freedom, wealth, family, adventure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;big 5 goals for the year

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;look at them and make sure they are in line with your values and they excite u&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;key behaviour and habits required to accomplish the big 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;once u know what&amp;#39;s important to you (see above), make sure the information you are studying is congruent to that&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;master 3 books than read 50&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it&amp;#39;s not a race to finish a book&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we want to see results in our lives and business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;focus on mastering a certain topic rather than simply focusing on finishing a book&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let your vision guide you, not your current circumstances, emotions, feelings, challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;2. Schedule everything - weekly review&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;our memory sucks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;everything I want to accomplish for this week MUST be on paper&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what did I get done and complete last week? pause and reflect.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what did i complete&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what went well, what didn&amp;#39;t go so well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;when did i waste time, when was i at my best&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;REVIEWING IS SO IMPORTANT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;what are your weekly commitments?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what must get done, NO MATTER WHAT, to solidify a successful week?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if you look back and got these things done, it&amp;#39;d be a success.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;u make sure they are intentional and strategic, tied to the big 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;u need to sell urself on why these commitments are important, or else u wont schedule and commit to it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;profit producing activities

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what 20-40% of your activities account for 60-80% of ur income&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the 3 or 4 things that had to happen weekly to make sure the business was moving forward&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;results must be created whether u feel liek it or not&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;what are your non-negotiables?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what habits or commitments you MUST do

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;consistently adding value&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;waking up early&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;working out 5 days a week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;who do i need to reach out to this week?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WHO should u reach out to that can help u get there quicker

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;elevate my thinking, results, maybe partner with, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;3. Seize each day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if you take care of ur days, ur weeks take care of themselves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;u dont set out to build a wall, you try to lay a brick as perfectly as a brick can be layed&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;focus the first hour of ur day in making urself STRONG (mentally, everything)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what are the 3 things i have to do to ensure I WIN the day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stay intentional&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;minimize distractions and interruptions

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what&amp;#39;s distracting me the most&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CREATE A PLAN to take care of these interruptions and distractions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Success orientation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unshakable Mindset
- you have to have a genuine confident belief that you could do anything you put your mind to
- find ways to maximize whatever resources u have&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create a make it or break it list
- who are your 5 growth friends, and who are your maintenance friends&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hang around smart people
- a HUGE difference&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;2nd Podcast: 6 months to 6 figures&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s delaying my purpose. I am meant to impact and empower people. I cannot delay my true calling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your back has to be against the wall before you are clear on what you wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Shift your circle of influence&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to be a millionaire, talk to a billionaire, you&amp;#39;ll get there quicker.
- he reached out to the top 5 people in his company
- made a list of those who hold him to a higher standard and lifting him
- made a list who was letting him off the hook&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;did not talk to those who were getting okay results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ask intelligent questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;- be fearless in reaching out to people&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;visualize with &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Increase your confidence&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;most people start off with a lot of excitement and then fluctuate until they fail&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;those who do what they &amp;quot;feel like&amp;quot; don&amp;#39;t do much&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I define my result rituals
- i figure out what results I needed to happen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;results come from habits, so put your habits &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;inspiration is short term&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;habits are long term&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;interrupt bad thought patterns&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;never listened to the news&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;only listened to successful people that u want to become&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;congruent to your goals&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;continual growth and learning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;!!!!### place people around you that won&amp;#39;t let u get complacent&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what am i excited about&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what am I grateful for&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what am I committed to making happen today no matter what&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BEWARE OF THIS ------&amp;gt; lack of momentum BEWARE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;REACH OUT to people at a higher level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>blah blah blah</title>
   <link href="http://adrianmcli.com/2015/01/21/draft/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-21T09:05:53-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://adrianmcli.com/2015/01/21/draft</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;http://www.jamesaltucher.com/2014/11/10-things-i-learned-while-interviewing-tony-robbins-about-his-new-book-money/&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>7 lessons from my first app failure</title>
   <link href="http://adrianmcli.com/2015/01/21/my-first-app-failure/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-21T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://adrianmcli.com/2015/01/21/my-first-app-failure</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the summer of 2013, I had the idea to make a mobile app, so I called up one of my friends and got to work. Over a year later, we launched &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.aheadstudios.talkalytics&quot;&gt;Texty Time&lt;/a&gt;. The project took so long and not too many people used it, so I decided I never wanted to touch or even think about it again. Recently, I was reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/levelsio&quot;&gt;@levelsio&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#39;s blog on how he planned to start &lt;a href=&quot;https://levels.io/12-startups-12-months/&quot;&gt;12 startups in 12 months&lt;/a&gt;. For a lot of these projects, he had a project debrief page where he talks about what he learned from each of them. Suddenly, I realized that I myself have attemped (and failed) at making something akin to a &amp;quot;startup&amp;quot; as well (albeit very very humble and basic). This is the story of what I learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As James Joyce said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mistakes are the portals of discovery&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#39;t even realize it was a &amp;quot;failure&amp;quot;, because I didn&amp;#39;t consider it to be a serious attempt. However, I realized that it would be an even bigger mistake if I failed to learn from the experience. So instead of running away from failure, here goes my attempt in trying to extract what lessons I&amp;#39;ve learned from my first app failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Development&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the development process, what affected us the most was our crippling technology, inefficient workflow, and overall lack of a market need for the product itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Crippling Technology&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology was a big part of what determines if an app succeeds or fails. First of all, there was the issue of being unfamiliar with the technology we used. I had never coded for Android before, so we tried a few different things at first. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming from web development, I tried PhoneGap because I believed in the power of HTML5. This was a mistake, because although it sounds great in theory, there was always too much lag and not enough control over how things would be rendered. The fact that we had to rely on web frameworks within a webview on an Android phone was bad enough, but dealing with a rapidly changing PhoneGap core made it even harder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Lesson #1: Do not use technology that is relatively immature and rapidly changing.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not only is it hard to make things work, it&amp;#39;s even harder to keep things from breaking. When a technology is rapidly changing at its core, a lot of the things you&amp;#39;ll be learning is going to change in the very near future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was also nearly impossible to find tutorials and documentation on the more obscure but commonly used aspects of the technology. There was a severe lack of libraries and limited community support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;#39;s important to get good at shipping a product, but how can you get good when you&amp;#39;re trying to hit a moving target?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a couple of months or so, we decided to switch to coding in Java on native Android so the user could enjoy a more responsive and lag-free experience. I soon realized that working on Android in Java was painfully low-level, and the Android API itself was too rigid (not good for prototyping fast). Android was also prone to version fragmentation, so we experienced some API changes throughout our development. Getting the app itself onto the app store and making sure we had all the in-app payment and everything setup properly was also a hassle. There was also the issue that Google could change anything on us at any time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were two major lessons here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Lesson #2: Do not use technology that is slow for prototyping.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Java as a language is known to be verbose. It is very slow in terms of prototyping things. It would always take me a very long time to get some very simple things set up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn a little bit about a lot of languages so you get a good idea of what&amp;#39;s out there and what you can use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not be afraid to try things out in a different language. Putting in a little time to figure out what works best is likely to be worth it in the long run.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Lesson #3: Do not develop in a market where there is a lack of control.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Control is one of the core aspects of entrepreneurship. If Google can force you to fit its guidelines (by threat of banning you), that is a bad sign.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always build something in a domain where you have the freedom to operate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All the hassle dealing with a controlled market will slow you down.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is only one way to make payments, to setup screenshots, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note that this is less of a problem if you&amp;#39;re already very familiar with the market and can already prototype very quickly (maybe because you are an expert in the domain).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Inefficient Workflow&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were just two people with full-time occupations doing this on the side. What we lacked was a sense of urgency. We probably could have done everything we did in 20% of the time. There were months in which we made no progress at all. This is not only an issue with personality, but also of vision and values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Lesson #4: Set hard deadlines to build a sense of urgency.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to prototype fast. You can&amp;#39;t afford to spend months working on something that nobody is going to use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to focus on this one thing. You cannot have other hobbies, because it will only distract you from finishing.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; ignore this lesson and do things as a side project, but just don&amp;#39;t expect it to be successful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Lack of Market Need&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no clearly defined target market. It just sounded like something cool that people would pay for. We were banking on people who might be desperate to know about how their relationships were like through their texts. However, it was obvious that we overestimated the market need for such a product. As Seth Godin put it, you need to understand the &amp;quot;tribe&amp;quot; that will become your loyal early adopters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn&amp;#39;t enough to simply know that there might be desperate individuals out there. We tried to scratch our own itch because it was something cool that we wanted. That&amp;#39;s all fine and good, but we should have prototyped and launched fast to really figure out how much market need there really was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Lesson #5: Do market research.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not try to scratch your own itch without further research (or better yet, launching).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand the people who you will eventually market to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clearly define the &amp;quot;tribe&amp;quot;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find out where they hang out&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be valuable to them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Marketing&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Pricing Too Low&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We set a freemium model for the app because we were scared people would not download it. In retrospect, we should have charged full price for the app. We were very timid and were scared that nobody would buy it if we did that. I now think that if what you made is not worth charging full price on day one, then you are almost certainly doomed. Social networks and other types of entrepreneurship aside, note that we are focusing on solo entrepreneurship through coding apps or webapps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Lesson #6: Aim to charge on day one, or re-evaluate your idea.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you don&amp;#39;t even believe in your product, why should anyone else?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you developed a product that was valuable, you should be able to see how you might pay for it yourself.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The fact that you are hesitant to charge for your product should get you to question whether your product is all that valuable to the market in the first place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could also use ads, but that is a mixed bag. Unless you know that people will have your app open for long periods of time, this is likely not going to work for you. This works well in games and radio apps, but for almost everything else it is unlikely to be a useful strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Lack of Focus&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admittedly, this is still an area which I don&amp;#39;t know much at all. However, there is a lot of great content out there, and I intend to read it. When we were marketing this app, we just haphazardly sent it to a lot of people we knew along with some random bloggers. There was no strategy at all, and we probably should have asked for more advice on the web along with doing a lot more research on our part. Later on, we even dumped some money into Google Adwords and Facebook ad campaigns, but to no avail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Lesson #7: Have a focus and strategy in marketing.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;#39;t just buy Facebook and Google ads haphazardly, but actually have a targeted approach.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use long tail keywords.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure to calcualate the cost of acquisition and conversion, even if it&amp;#39;s just an estimate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look for the &amp;#39;tribe&amp;#39; and seek out what others have done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;message&quot;&gt;Launching fast eliminates a whole class of problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a very costly lesson. A year of your life (albeit mostly part-time) is a high price to pay. A lot of these problems and issues would have come to light much sooner if I set myself a a tight deadline and prototyped fast. I now realize that prototyping fast is not just for the sake of efficiency, but it also completely eliminates a whole bunch of problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, a lot of the problems I experienced above could have come to light a lot sooner or even completely avoided if I only just prototyped faster and launched sooner.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Code Snippets: Part 1</title>
   <link href="http://adrianmcli.com/2015/01/21/code-snippets-1/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-21T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://adrianmcli.com/2015/01/21/code-snippets-1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I learn a lot while building things, and I don&amp;#39;t want to forget what I&amp;#39;ve learned. It has happened many times in the past, so this time I have decided to keep a record of what I have learned so that I won&amp;#39;t have to redo any research that I&amp;#39;ve already done. Hopefully, this will be useful to other people as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following is a list of things I learned recently about how to make websites with Meteor. A lot of these might be a lot more straight-forward or simple if you&amp;#39;re doing a plain HTML file, but with Meteor there are some things to keep in mind. I&amp;#39;ve also included some non-Meteor specific techniques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;1. Making a nice full-length header bar based on Foundation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://foundation.zurb.com/docs/components/topbar.html&quot;&gt;Top Bar&lt;/a&gt; documentation is great. However, since it relies on some fancy javascript listener, you have to apply the listener every time the template is loaded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just add the following code inside the corresponding javascript file for your template:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Template&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;layout&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;rendered&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(){&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;document&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;foundation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;topbar&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;reflow&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// apply listener&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;};&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2. Change an element&amp;#39;s style when the user scrolls down&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the user scrolls down 50 pixels, the element with the &lt;code&gt;.top-bar&lt;/code&gt; class will have the class &lt;code&gt;.scrolled&lt;/code&gt; added to it. When the page is scrolled to the top, the &lt;code&gt;.scrolled&lt;/code&gt; class will be removed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just add the following code inside the corresponding javascript file for your template:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Template&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;layout&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;rendered&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(){&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;document&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;ready&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;window&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;scroll&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;window&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;scrollTop&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;.top-bar&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;addClass&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;scrolled&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;.top-bar&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;removeClass&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;scrolled&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;};&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;3. Autocomplete or Typeahead&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one was really frustrating, but I finally figured out how to do it. I always find it frustrating when people ask about how to do something, and then the creator tells them to just take a look at the example but doesn&amp;#39;t give specific instructions. This is understandable, but what is even more frustrating is when people eventually figure it out but doesn&amp;#39;t explain how they figured it out. Well, the buck stops here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;meteor add sergeyt:typeahead&lt;/code&gt; in the terminal to add the typeahead package.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the following input element in your HTML template:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;input&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;form-control typeahead&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;name=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;team&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;type=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;text&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
       &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;placeholder=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;NBA teams&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
       &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;autocomplete=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;off&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;spellcheck=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;off&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
       &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;data-source=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;nba&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;/&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put the following code inside the corresponding javascript file for your template:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Template&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;demo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;helpers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;({&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;nba&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Nba&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;find&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;().&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;fetch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;().&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;map&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;){&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;it&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Template&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;demo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;rendered&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;Meteor&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;typeahead&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;inject&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;.typeahead&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;));&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data-source in the HTML specifies &lt;code&gt;nba&lt;/code&gt;. So the typeahead.js library will make note of that and run the &lt;code&gt;nba&lt;/code&gt; function in the template helper. However, for that to work we have to let the typeahead.js library know to listen to the appropriate classes. This is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://atmospherejs.com/sergeyt/typeahead&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; to the package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also, don&amp;#39;t forget to style the dropdown. Here&amp;#39;s mine for reference:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/fb007a065cd5c0bef31d.js&quot;&gt; &lt;/script&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following techniques are not Meteor specific, but they are valuable lessons I learned which should be useful in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;4. Full Screen Background Images&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned this from this &lt;a href=&quot;http://css-tricks.com/perfect-full-page-background-image/&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;. Making the pretty full screen backgrounds that are popular these days is easy thanks to HTML5, all we have to do is use the following CSS:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot; data-lang=&quot;css&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;html&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; 
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;background&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;sx&quot;&gt;url(images/bg.jpg)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;no-repeat&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;center&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;center&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;fixed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; 
  &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;webkit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;background&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;cover&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;moz&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;background&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;cover&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;o&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;background&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;cover&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;background&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;size&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;cover&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;4. Full Screen Sections&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another simple CSS trick. It&amp;#39;s not really even a trick, but it&amp;#39;s a trick to me because I didn&amp;#39;t know about it before. This &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ckor/make-full-screen-sections-with-1-line-of-css-b82227c75cbd&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; made it very simple to create divs that are 100% of the viewport height.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot; data-lang=&quot;css&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;height&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;vh&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;5. Sticky Footer&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ryanfait.com/sticky-footer/&quot;&gt;Ryan Fait&lt;/a&gt; came up with a CSS sticky footer that &amp;quot;just works&amp;quot;. I have reproduced it here for record&amp;#39;s sake:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot; data-lang=&quot;css&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;margin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;body&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;height&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;100%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.wrapper&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;min-height&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;100%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;height&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;auto&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;!important&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;/* This line and the next line are not necessary unless you need IE6 support */&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;height&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;100%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;margin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;auto&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;-155px&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;/* the bottom margin is the negative value of the footer&amp;#39;s height */&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.footer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.push&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;height&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;155px&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;/* .push must be the same height as .footer */&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Providing Unique Value</title>
   <link href="http://adrianmcli.com/2015/01/16/providing-unique-value/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-16T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://adrianmcli.com/2015/01/16/providing-unique-value</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A while back, I found &lt;a href=&quot;http://moz.com/blog/how-to-provide-unique-value-in-your-content-whiteboard-friday&quot;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://moz.com/blog/how-to-provide-unique-value-in-your-content-whiteboard-friday&quot;&gt;DigitalPoint.com&lt;/a&gt;, an industry news site about business software. The number one rule of business (as I have recognized) is to create value. But how do you know if you&amp;#39;re creating something valuable? Well this video seemed to explain just that. The video focuses on SEO, but the value of the content here is much more than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below, I will be revealing my personalized summary of this video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Notes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does unique value really mean?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Modern Criteria for Content&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One-of-a-kind&lt;/strong&gt; - The content itself must be original; it does not appear elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevant&lt;/strong&gt; - The content must match the intent of the reader. You can sometimes have words that match a user&amp;#39;s search query, but unless the topic of your content matches the same topic that&amp;#39;s in the user&amp;#39;s head, it won&amp;#39;t be relevant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Helpful&lt;/strong&gt; - You must resolve the query of the reader in a useful and efficient manner. You have to provide that feeling you get when you search for an answer to something and you get &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; the page you were looking for.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uniquely Valuable&lt;/strong&gt; - Provide something that is &amp;quot;unavailable or hard to get elsewhere&amp;quot;. The rest of the summary talks about this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Great UX&lt;/strong&gt; - The content must be &amp;quot;easy and pleasurable to consume anywhere on any device&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Unique Value&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most difficult part of the above checklist is &lt;strong&gt;unique value&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A massive upgrade in aggregation, accessibility and design&lt;/strong&gt; - You want to be creating something that is so understandable, so accessible, and so well-designed that the user might say to themselves, &amp;quot;I&amp;#39;ve seen this before, but never like &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt;&amp;quot;. Create an enjoyable experience around something that people may, in the past, have had to take the time to search around and read a lot to find it. Give it all to them &lt;strong&gt;in one spot&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provide information that is available nowhere else&lt;/strong&gt; - Information is not the same as data. The same data might be out there already, but information is a much broader concept: it&amp;#39;s the idea inside a person&amp;#39;s head. It&amp;#39;s not about having a specific number or specific sentence or phrase, but it&amp;#39;s about giving the user the ability to say, &lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;without this site, I never would have found the answers I sought!&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; The data was out there, but the information was not available until now. This might be formed by unique novel way of aggregation or presentation. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An example is Walk Score, which scored the ease of living in certain locations by using walking as a primary form of transportation. It aggregated a lot of data, but it also allowed you to easily compare between cities. This was its unique value proposition that you could not get anywhere else.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content that is presented with a massively differentiated voice or style&lt;/strong&gt; - This can be viewed as a writer or artist&amp;#39;s individual voice or style. The content must &lt;strong&gt;emotionally resonate&lt;/strong&gt; in a unique way. The is the differece between something like an ASAP Science video on YouTube versus reading a Wikipedia article on the same topic. The information is the same, but the voice is different (and much more enjoyable to take in).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;#39;t have to tackle all three at once, but you need to be aiming for at least one of these three if you want to be uniquely valuable. Ask yourself if what you are making hits the above points, if it doesn&amp;#39;t then ask yourself if it is really worth doing. To truly provide value, it&amp;#39;s not enough to just publish, you have to create something people actually want.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Book Summary: The 7 Day Startup</title>
   <link href="http://adrianmcli.com/2015/01/15/the-7-day-startup/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-15T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://adrianmcli.com/2015/01/15/the-7-day-startup</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I first heard about this book from this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/startups/comments/2rz8aj/here_is_how_i_built_my_first_mvp_in_less_than_a/&quot;&gt;Reddit post&lt;/a&gt;. After Googling the book title, I found out that the theme of the book was to teach you to finally stop being a wantrepreneur and start executing on something. The story of the author, Dan Norris, is that he spent a year developing a startup which didn&amp;#39;t really go anywhere, and was actually going to have to look for a job because he was running out of money. However, with just a couple weeks left, he cranked out a wildly successful business by launching in 7 days. I thought this was very intriguing, so I bought it and gave it a read. Below are the major ideas I&amp;#39;ve been able to extract from this book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://wpcurve.com/the-7-day-startup/&quot;&gt;Official Site&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/The-Day-Startup-Learn-Launch-ebook/dp/B00NZFKB8S&quot;&gt;Amazon Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;A note about my process&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When reading the book, I typed up a lot of raw notes into a text file. In making this book summary, I am essentially trying to summarize the main points I&amp;#39;ve learned into a neat format so that I can look back at it later on. The bulk of this post is a book summary mixed with my own personal thoughts as well. As a result, I have written things below that aren&amp;#39;t in the book, but are inspired by the ideas in the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that this summary is what stood out to me and in no way does it represent the full scope of the book. The book goes into a lot more detail with a lot of links and other resources as well. I did not read the chapters of the book slated for what to do after the launch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Notes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is very important to &lt;em&gt;avoid&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sexy ideas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asking for opinions on your ideas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making assumptions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we should simply let people &lt;em&gt;vote with their wallets&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;message&quot;&gt;Things may come to those who wait ... but only things left by those who hustle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;3 Core Essential Elements&lt;/strong&gt; required in entrepreneurship is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Idea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Execution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hustle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it is very rare that one person can encompass all three. This is why it is often suggested that you find a partner who can help you out in the area (or areas) that you are not so proficient with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For execution, in the short term it is to communicate your idea out to the world by launching &lt;em&gt;fast&lt;/em&gt;. In the medium term, however:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;execution is your ability to present your idea just as well as the best ideas in the world&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of hustle, it can be simply described as &lt;strong&gt;relentlessly pursuing what needs to be done&lt;/strong&gt; at the time. For an early stage startup, this is generally about spending your time on the things that are most likely to bring you customers. So in a way, it can be said that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;message&quot;&gt;Hustle = Getting Customers (through any way possible)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so it follows, since &lt;strong&gt;after launch&lt;/strong&gt; you need to get more people paying you. You have to relentlessly pursue your best method of getting customers, and not the stuff you naturally gravitate to. Let me emphasize that again, it&amp;#39;s about &lt;strong&gt;getting customers!!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Validation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Validation does not work when the answer is not a definite yes (some refer to this as &amp;quot;if not f*ck yes, then no&amp;quot;). The idea here is that a lot of the current validation techniques are rather low commitment and do not actually give you much information on what the market actually wants. People can give e-mails, comments, likes, and really almost anything else, but you don&amp;#39;t know what they are really willing to pay for unless you make them pay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People don&amp;#39;t know what they &lt;em&gt;don&amp;#39;t&lt;/em&gt; want until they are forced to open their wallets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Time&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;message&quot;&gt;Do not give yourself the time to make assumptions. Launch first and decide based on real customer behaviour&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BEWARE OF HAVING TOO MUCH TIME - you will be inefficient&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You must &lt;em&gt;beware of having too much time&lt;/em&gt; because this will lead you to become inefficient. Just like how students can work extremely efficiently right before a deadline, the reverse is also true: having too much time will make you extremely inefficient. You must maintain that sense of urgency, and one way of doing that is to give yourself a really short deadline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a long way out, you make up tasks that you think are important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;7 Day Schedule&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day 1: Picking an &lt;strong&gt;idea&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day 2: Coming up with your &lt;strong&gt;MVP&lt;/strong&gt; (what you will launch on Day 7)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day 3: Picking a &lt;strong&gt;name&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day 4: Making a &lt;strong&gt;landing page&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day 5: Getting in front of people; &lt;strong&gt;Marketing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day 6: &lt;strong&gt;Measuring&lt;/strong&gt; success (goal and target setting)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day 7: &lt;strong&gt;Launch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 1 - The Idea&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;9 Elements of a Bootstrapped Business Idea&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enjoyable daily tasks&lt;/strong&gt; - You have to make sure that the tasks you will be doing for this business can be enjoyable. Otherwise, people who actually enjoy those tasks will outwork you and succeed while crushing you along the way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Product/founder fit&lt;/strong&gt; - Don&amp;#39;t stack the odds against yourself, stack them in your favour. Think about what skills you have, what you might be known for, and most importantly where you can provide the most value. For example, it may not be a good idea to pick an industry where you have absolutely no knowledge about when you are an expert in many other things. Don&amp;#39;t focus on making money, think about creating value.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scalable business model&lt;/strong&gt; - There are some business ideas which simply do not scale. Think about how you can allow your business to replicate profits over and over. Don&amp;#39;t go with business ideas where there is a clear limit to your profit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operates profitably without the founder&lt;/strong&gt; - Maybe not when you launch, but at some point you would like to have the business automated so that it doesn&amp;#39;t consume all of your time. A business that consumes all of your time is just another job.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An asset you can sell&lt;/strong&gt; - The goal is to create something so valuable that you can sell it away (even if you don&amp;#39;t want to). Think about what you build as a long term asset. For example, having lots of site traffic may be great, but having a large e-mail list is much better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Large market potential&lt;/strong&gt; - This is pretty self explanatory, but it will require you to actually think about the problem and do some research. Also of note, sometimes the fact that there isn&amp;#39;t anything out there similar to your idea may be a bad sign that there is no market need to begin with.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tap into pain or pleasure differentiators&lt;/strong&gt; - The key to differentiating yourself is to look at current solutions and see where there is friction or annoyances. Usually, people experience pain points during a particular task, and experience pleasure points after the painful task is finished. Ask yourself if your idea sufficiently attacks these two angles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unique lead generation advantage&lt;/strong&gt; - How will you find your customers? Does the solution make you and your company unique? You need to be differentiated in the tradtional sense as well, the idea should allow you to catch the attention of people by virtue of its unique value proposition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ability to launch quickly&lt;/strong&gt; - Pretty simple, don&amp;#39;t choose something you can&amp;#39;t launch and modify quickly. If you are going to build something so complicated that it would take months, then you probably won&amp;#39;t be able to modify and change it fast enough later on as you learn from your customers. If it would take you longer than 7 days to come up with a prototype, either get better at making prototypes or find a better idea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avoid low barriers of entry&lt;/strong&gt; - Also of note is to make sure you don&amp;#39;t pick ideas where there is a very low barrier to entry. It would be so easy for anyone to simply catch up to you right away if it was so easy. As you pick your idea, keep in mind that you have to be creating every single day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An interesting idea from the book is that we should ask not what tools people might want, but &lt;strong&gt;what tools people are already paying for&lt;/strong&gt;. This is what it means to relieve the pain points without cultivating new behaviours from customers. By developing something completely new and out of the blue, we have to coax our potential customers into thinking they might need or want our tool. However, if it is something they are already bleeding money into, then you can help them out there with your product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;message&quot;&gt;Are people &lt;em&gt;already&lt;/em&gt; paying for a solution to the same problem?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Actionable steps:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brainstorm a bunch of ideas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluate them against the 9 element checklist &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 2 - The MVP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a common mistake to over-minimize and under-viablize your Minimal Viable Product (&amp;quot;MVP&amp;quot;). Do not put out an MVP that is much worse than current products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put up screenshots, explain the product&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Client pays, make them do a few actions (for data collection purposes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tell them their product will be ready soon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Call and talk them through what&amp;#39;s being done; give them the product&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forget about automating everything, figure out what you can do manually now to launch within a week. This may be hard, and probably very painful too. But it&amp;#39;s even more painful to have worked on automating the task for months just to find out no one wants to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do not worry&lt;/em&gt; about how &lt;strong&gt;ugly or painful&lt;/strong&gt; it looks on our end, what matters is that it looks like it will solve the customer&amp;#39;s problem. Always make sure you can &lt;strong&gt;deliver on customer expectations.&lt;/strong&gt; Even if it means doing more manual work, make sure you can mimic the customer experience as quickly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;message&quot;&gt;Focus &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; on what you need to do to make the MVP something people would pay for. Just &lt;em&gt;prove&lt;/em&gt; that people would pay for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A final note: &lt;strong&gt;Do not do free versions&lt;/strong&gt;. Charge on the first day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can you perform a service or offer a product to real customers?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How will you get them to pay you on launch day?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How close will your MVP be to the final vision of your product?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What can you do manually (hint: probably everything)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What can you do yourself instead of delegating?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How can you make your offer as real as possible for the end customer?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Actionable steps:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write down what you will launch on day 7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What will your customers get?

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is included?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is excluded?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What will be automated?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What will be manually done (in the short term)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 3 - The Name&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#39;t overthink it, we are going for an &amp;quot;acceptable&amp;quot; name. Just come up with 10 names that aren&amp;#39;t ridiculous. Here is a checklist to consider:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is it taken?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is it simple?

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;don&amp;#39;t make up words&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;don&amp;#39;t misspell words&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fewer than 12 characters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is it easy to say out loud?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you like it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does it make sense for your idea (this is a bonus)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Broader is better (your business will probably change anyway)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Actionable Steps:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate 10 names&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go through the checklist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 4 - Build the site (in one day for less than $100)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 Options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a site to capture e-mails before you launch in 4 days time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a site that pre-sells your product before you launch it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create the actual sales page you will use on launch day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author goes into a lot of detail (step-by-step) on how to create a WordPress site. I personally will not be using WordPress so I didn&amp;#39;t take notes on this part. Just make sure to have a pay button on day 7 when you launch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some useful sites:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.elegantthemes.com/&quot;&gt;ElegantThemes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mailchimp.com/&quot;&gt;MailChimp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.getdrip.com/&quot;&gt;Drip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mixergy.com/Master-Class/Copywriting/TheCopywritingChecklist.pdf&quot;&gt;Copywriting Checklist (by Dane Maxwell)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 5 - Marketing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Content Marketing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#39;re searching for something, then other people probably are as well. Scratching your own itch may not work for business ideas, but it can work for developing a marketing plan. Find a gap in what you are searching for and produce detailed blog posts devoted to those topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topic ideas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In-depth content based around customer problems that your solution solves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make actionable and useful content to your target&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure it&amp;#39;s interesting to the audience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While doing this, make sure to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Capture e-mails&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on valuable content, don&amp;#39;t worry about SEO at this point&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try different mediums

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;blog post&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;infographic &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;video&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;podcasts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ebooks &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;whitepapers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One important thing to stress is that you must &lt;strong&gt;create LOTS of content&lt;/strong&gt;. Also, consider doing guest posts and interviews on other people&amp;#39;s blogs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Start Sending Emails&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try to build a list before launch day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Building a List&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add people you already know early on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a landing page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Send out high quality relevant information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give away something relevant and valuable to get people on the list

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;software&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;plugins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;templates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ebooks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;training courses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create good blog posts and create content relevant to the post that you can give away

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even if it&amp;#39;s something kind of trivial (like a simple checklist or template), because having something for the reader to download adds to perceived value&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lot of people download things just to see what it is, and in those cases you&amp;#39;ll probably leave a longer lasting impression in their minds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep your emails personal and encourage people to reply

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build goodwill&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other things to try:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Podcasting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forums and Online Groups

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join a forum, be an active member, build trust&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consider joining a paid group in your niche&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guest blogging

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consider doing a guest post for an industry you quit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wherever your idea or even your self and past history is relevant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Listing sites

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lot of examples here, see book or Google a bit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every industry have sites that list businesses in different ways&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Webinars

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;John Dumas&amp;#39; strategy

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build up a large audience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gave away an eBook as a freebie, got your e-mail, then told you about a free webinar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The webinars were super helpful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For those who are interested in more info, he has a special deal for membership in the community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presenting

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local, in-person events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doing free work

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reach out and do things for free&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Media Coverage

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pull lists of relevant journalists to contact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See who covered other entrepreneurs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pay attention to parts of your own business that could be newsworthy; look for &lt;em&gt;stories&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drop everything to be featured in the media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk about yourselves all the time, be transparent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Send your own best articles to other sites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Chapter Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, it&amp;#39;s just about &amp;quot;getting your message out to qualified people as efficiently as possible&amp;quot;. Do it in a way that utilizes your unique strengths and gets you customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action:&lt;/strong&gt; Put together a rough plan for the first week or two of launch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 6 - Set Targets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do we know if we&amp;#39;ve failed or not? Rampant success and immediate flops are obvious, but what do we do with everything in between? Focus on the &lt;em&gt;One Metric That Matters (&amp;quot;OMTM&amp;quot;)&lt;/em&gt; at different stages of the business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During launch, focus on the number of people who signup and pay. Set a reasonable number that takes into consideration your reach, the marketing efforts, and price point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#39;t set crazy targets, because overly aggressive targets can demotivate you. Shoot for a few customers early on and a realistic monthly growth rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WP Curve Example (very modest):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 customers in the first month (or $500 in monthly recurring revenue)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10% per month for at least six months&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monthly Recurring Revenue (&amp;quot;MRR&amp;quot;) has always been the metric of choice because it comes in every month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that the OMTM can change over time. There is a chart in the book that talks about what OMTM is suitable for each phase of your startup and hot to measure it. This is a &lt;strong&gt;really important tool&lt;/strong&gt;, so make sure you get the book and read it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I skimmed some of the content past that, but the notes above is the bulk of what I learned in terms of getting to launch quickly and smartly. Some of the other content that talks about what to do after launch seems great too, but it&amp;#39;s not something I&amp;#39;ll get around to reading just yet. I hope that whoever reads this far into this post finds the above to be helpful!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Beginning</title>
   <link href="http://adrianmcli.com/2015/01/14/the-beginning/"/>
   <updated>2015-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://adrianmcli.com/2015/01/14/the-beginning</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the story of how I will attempt to start a profitable online business in a year and a half. I have an employment contract that will end in June of 2016 and that&amp;#39;s why I am on such a tight deadline. Nevertheless, I&amp;#39;ve always believed in &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parkinson%27s_law&quot;&gt;Parkinson&amp;#39;s Law&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;work expands so as to fill the time available for its completion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll probably blog about it a little more later on, but this is something I have tested numerous times. I adhere very strongly to the idea of &amp;quot;sink or swim&amp;quot;, or in other words: I know that if I put myself in the deep end, I&amp;#39;ll learn to swim. The hard part is having the courage to drop myself into the water without any way out. And so, here begins my journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;A Productivity Framework&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best (and simplest) posts I&amp;#39;ve read on productivity and personal development is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lifehack.org/articles/productivity/the-only-2-tricks-you-need-for-maximum-productivity.html&quot;&gt;The Only 2 Tricks You Need for Maximum Productivity&lt;/a&gt;. It can be summarized in the following two points:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plot your day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carve out time each week to reflect and calibrate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result of this, there are a couple things I am aiming to do. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;A Daily Habit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s so important to develop a daily habit. In July of 2014, I tried to wake up at 4:30am every day for 30 days. In those 30 days, I was so productive and I just felt great overall. I would wake up and run for half an hour, and then I would come home to read a book over breakfast. It was my personal development morning and I can see the power of this multiply if I made it a permanent pattern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;#39;s even more important is having an idea of what you will be doing for any particular day. The link above suggested that we take 10 minutes out of every morning to plan this. But why not shift those 10 minutes to the night before? This way, the moment we get up, we know what we need to do. There is zero friction, just get up and do. For this purpose, I have set up a whiteboard where every night I will write down the things I&amp;#39;ll do in the following day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;7-Day Evaluations and 28-Day Evaluations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To keep myself on track, I have decided to do an evaluation of my progress every 7 days, and also another more macro evaluation of my progress every 28 days. These evaluations are also kind of like summaries for what worked and what didn&amp;#39;t work over the previous span of time. This allows me to better keep track of my progress and not so easily forget what I learned along the way. For the purposes of this blog, I&amp;#39;ll only be posting the 28-day evaluations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;That&amp;#39;s it for now&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to make sure I&amp;#39;m not trying too many things all at once, because what usually ends up happening is that I get nothing done at all. I look forward to writing the first 28-day evaluation!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
